looksmart.com 2002-11-20

# LookSmart About Us

LookSmart has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to protecting your privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for the following LookSmart sites: [www.looksmart.com](http://www.looksmart.com/) and [listings.looksmart.com](http://listings.looksmart.com/). 

The following questions are answered below: 

  1. What information does LookSmart collect?
  2. What organization is collecting the information?
  3. What does LookSmart do with the data it collects?
  4. With whom does LookSmart share data?
  5. What choices are available regarding collection, use and distribution of the information (Opt Out Policy)?
  6. How can you update or correct your information?
  7. How can you delete your information or deactivate your membership?
  8. What procedures have been designed to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under LookSmart's control?
  9. What about privacy policies for sites linked to LookSmart?
  10. What happens to my information if LookSmart merges with or is sold to another company?

We suggest that you practice reasonable discretion when you provide any site with personal information. Note also that whenever you post personal information in publicly accessible places, this information becomes available to anyone with access to the Internet. Therefore, we recommend that you refrain from posting any information you do not want seen in these public areas. You should feel free to contact any site that requests personal information from you if you have any questions regarding its policies. 

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site or your dealings with this Web site, email [privacy@looksmart.net](mailto:privacy@looksmart.net). 

**1.  What information does LookSmart collect? At different times, LookSmart may collect six types of information about you.**

First, we use a feature of your browser called a cookie to assign identification to your computer. The unique user ID contained within your cookie automatically identifies your computer — but not you — to our servers every time you visit our site. Cookies by themselves cannot be used to find out the identity of any user but may be correlated with identity information in our log files. You can turn the cookies feature off by using your browser's preference options, but you may not be able to utilize some services properly. 

Second, we keep track of your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our Web site. Your IP address is also used to gather broad demographic information about you, such as your location and your Internet service provider. LookSmart may also collect aggregate information on how our users are utilizing the site. This might include information regarding traffic patterns through the site and search queries. 

Third, we log browser types, access times, URLs from which visitors came to our site and URLs viewed by visitors while on our site. Except as otherwise stated in this privacy policy, we do not provide this information to third parties, except in aggregate form. 

Fourth, at specific times we may ask you to provide us with personal information in order for you to register for a service or to enter a sweepstakes. This information may include but is not limited to your name and email address. You may always choose not to provide us with this information; however, this may limit our ability to provide you with a specific service or offer you personalized content. 

Fifth, we may collect credit card information if you register for any paid services on our site, such as LookListings Small Business on LookSmart. We make our best efforts to protect credit card transactions through encryption, although we cannot guarantee complete security. In order to complete a transaction, payment information may be transferred through one of our partners who process such information. 

Sixth, we also collect information through the use of "pixel tags" included in email messages we may send to you. Pixel tags are tiny graphic files, not visible to the human eye, that are included in HTML-encoded email messages. When such a message is opened in an HTML-capable email program, the recipient's computer will access our server to retrieve the pixel tag file, allowing us to record and store, along with the recipient's email address, the date and time the recipient viewed the email message, that the recipient's email program is capable of receiving HTML-encoded email, and other standard logging information. The pixel tag also may see or read cookies. 

Seventh, we contract with Coremetrics, a service partner, to provide us with a data collection and reporting service for our LookListings Small Business services. We also have asked Coremetrics to store certain legacy data that we received from visitors to the LookListings Small Business part of our web site (which may include email addresses) prior to our relationship with them, so that we may access this information via their reporting service and for no other purpose. If you access the LookListings Small Business part of our web site, Coremetrics may collect information about you on our behalf. For further information, including how to opt out, please see: <http://www.coremetrics.com/info_eluminate2.html>. 

**2.  What organization is collecting the information?**

LookSmart usually collects the requested information. However, LookSmart has chosen select partners in order to provide you with full-service Web sites. LookSmart's partners provide users with services such as classified ads. In order to use these areas, it may be necessary to enter information that then goes to our partner and is not kept by LookSmart. The areas of our sites in which partners are collecting information may be cobranded with our partners' logos. 

If you have any questions regarding who is collecting or receiving the information you provide on our sites, please contact us. 

Some of the sections in which we use content partners include, but are not limited to, the following: 

  * Localized content 
  * Horoscopes 
  * Weather 
  * LookListings Small Business

If you have questions regarding the privacy policy or data collection practices of one of our content partners, please contact that partner directly. 

Some of our content partners, as well as advertisers who display ads on our site, may use cookies or otherwise independently collect information from you. We do not control their collection and use of information or their use of cookies or have access to the information contained in or related to those cookies. 

**3.  What does LookSmart do with the data it collects?**

Whenever LookSmart collects data, the data is intended to tailor or improve the experience of visitors to our site. From the data collected we can customize content and advertising based on the user's preferences. We use information from a cookie (a feature of your browser used to assign identification to your computer to count and track site visits in the aggregate) to differentiate between unique users, personalize the site for each unique user, to control the frequency of individual advertisements directed to individual computers, and other purposes. In all cases, specific personal information is not shared with our advertisers, except as otherwise stated in this privacy policy. 

We use IP addresses to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our Web sites. IP addresses may be disclosed to a third party if we believe in good faith that the law or legal process requires it, or to protect the rights or property of LookSmart or others. 

When you register for unique services on our sites, we collect additional information from you in order to provide you with those specific services and to personalize your experience on the site. We may use information to target offerings that may be of interest to you and/or to analyze aggregate user data in order to improve our services. In addition, several other services on LookSmart (such as the weather and horoscope services) utilize a cookie to track your selections during your visit (such as your city or astrological sign so that we can supply you with correct services and information). That cookie may be supplied by LookSmart or one of its content partners. 

On occasion we will email bulletins to provide you with information that we think you will find useful, including information about new products and services. We might also contact you to see if you are interested in participating in market research regarding LookSmart. Many of our sites also send a monthly or bimonthly newsletter by email to their users. It is our policy to send these promotional emails only to customers who give us permission to do so. In every such email, we will also have instructions on how to unsubscribe and avoid receiving any future emails from us. Please see our Opt Out Policy section below. LookSmart also may contact you by email to respond to customer-service complaints you have submitted, to address a problem affecting your use of the service or to verify your account information if you submit a password request. If at any time you feel you have received e-mail from LookSmart that you did not request, please send your concerns, along with a copy of the e-mail, to [privacy@looksmart.net](mailto:privacy@looksmart.net). 

Users who have submitted a site suggestion through LookListings Small Business may receive separate promotional information on occasion, by email or telephone call. 

**4.  With whom does LookSmart share data?**

LookSmart may disclose your personal information to our business partners in order to provide you with the services you have requested, or to companies that offer a cobranded version of one of our sites. If you have questions regarding the privacy policy or data-collection practices of one of our content partners, please contact that partner directly. LookSmart does not have control over and is not responsible for the data collection and use practices of our business partners. 

We also may disclose your personal information to a third party if we believe in good faith that the law or legal process requires it, to protect the rights or property of LookSmart or others, to assist our e-mail vendor with resolving complaints about unsolicited e-mail, or as otherwise described in this privacy policy. 

We may share aggregate demographic information with our advertisers or information collection companies, but will not reveal any personally identifiable information in these instances. 

**5.  What choices are available regarding collection, use and distribution of the information (Opt Out Policy)?**

Many of the services available on our sites provide you with the opportunity to opt out of receiving communications from us and our partners. In addition, in our email communications, we will have instructions on how to unsubscribe so that you will not receive any future emails from us if you so choose. 

As previously noted, you may always choose to not provide us with any of the information we request; however, this may limit our ability to provide you with a specific service or limit our ability to offer personalized content. 

**6.  How can you update or correct your information?**

LookSmart does not currently have a method for users to change their user information. In the case of personalized services, you will be able to modify your user information through personalization links on those pages. 

We contract with Coremetrics, a service partner, to provide us with a data collection and reporting service for our LookListings Small Business services. If you access the LookListings Small Business part of our web site, Coremetrics may collect information about you on our behalf. For further information, including how to opt out, please see: <http://www.coremetrics.com/info_eluminate2.html>. 

**7.  How can you delete your information or deactivate your membership?**

If you would like to deactivate your membership with one of the services offered on LookSmart, please visit that service on the site. LookSmart currently does not have a method for completely deleting user information from our database. However, deleting the cookie stored on your computer will cause you to be perceived as a new user with no known user data. You may also change a setting in your browser, instructing it not to accept cookies, but this could prevent you from receiving some LookSmart services. 

**8.  What procedures have been designed to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under LookSmart's control?**

Except as otherwise stated in this privacy policy, LookSmart has taken measures to ensure that information that is not publicly available through its sites is accessible only to the user who initially entered the information or to authorized personnel at LookSmart or its partners, and only after a password has been entered. 

**9.  What about privacy policies for sites linked to LookSmart?**

As a Web directory, LookSmart contains many links to Web sites not affiliated with LookSmart. These sites have their own policies and practices with respect to online privacy, and LookSmart cannot be responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these unaffiliated Web sites. In addition, in certain instances a LookSmart advertiser may ask you for personal information. LookSmart cannot be responsible for the privacy practices of its advertisers. 

**10. What happens to my information if LookSmart merges with or is sold to another company?**

It is possible that LookSmart and/or any of our assets may be acquired. In such a transaction, customer information may be transferred to the acquiring entity. While we will endeavor to require the successor company to maintain this privacy policy, we cannot guarantee that our policy will remain in effect. 

**Notification of Changes**

This policy may be revised over time as new features are added to the Web site. We will post our new privacy policy, along with the date of its last revision, prominently so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information, and whether we will disclose it to anyone. Please check this Web page for information about revisions to our privacy policy. 

**Contact Information**

If you have any questions about this privacy policy or about LookSmart's information collection practices, please contact us at [privacy@looksmart.net](mailto:privacy@looksmart.net).
